And a massive welcome back one more time to LM engineering.
LM 엔지니어링에 다시 한번 큰 박수를 보내주세요
We are in week three, day two and we are getting into open source models.
3주 차, 2일째입니다 오픈 소스 모델로 들어가고 있죠
So as a reminder you can already do frontier models back to front.
다시 말씀드리지만 개척 시대 모델은 이미 거꾸로 할 수 있어요
You can build multimodal AI assistants.
다중 모듈 인공지능 보조를 만들 수 있어요
And now you're comfortable looking at the hugging face hub, looking at models and data sets and spaces.
이제 안는 얼굴 허브를 편하게 볼 수 있습니다 모델, 데이터 세트, 공간을 보는 거죠
And you can run code using Google Colab.
구글 콜라브로 코드를 실행할 수 있어요
So today we're going to look at Hugging Face Transformers library and discuss the fact that there are
오늘은 얼굴 트랜스포머 껴안기 라이브러리를 살펴보고 API 종류에 대해
two different types of API, two different levels that you can work with transformers at one level,
얘기해 볼게요 두 가지 레벨로 트랜스포머와 작업할 수 있어요 더 높은 레벨은 파이프라인이라는
the higher level API is called pipelines, and that's what we'll be working with mostly today, including
API로 오늘 주로 작업할 거예요 파이프라인을 이용해 텍스트, 이미지,
generating text, images and sound using pipelines.
소리를 생성하는 걸 포함해서요
So let's just talk for a moment about these two different API levels.
잠시 다른 API 레벨에 대해 얘기해보죠
So there are these two modes of interacting with the hugging face code.
안는 얼굴 코드와 상호 작용하는 방식은 두 가지예요
One of them is if you want to carry out a standard, everyday typical task in what we'd call inference,
그 중 하나는 표준을 수행하고 싶을 때죠 추론이라는 것을 위한 매일의 전형적인 작업이나 런타임에
or running a model at runtime given an input to get an output.
모델을 실행할 때요 입력값을 받아 getput을 얻는 거죠
And hugging face has wonderfully packaged this up into a high level interface that's super easy to use,
얼굴을 안는 방법은 패키지로 아주 쉽게 상위 레벨 인터페이스에 넣을 수 있게 해줍니다.
and that provides you with a rapid way to get going, generating text, and doing a number of everyday
빠르게 진행할 수 있게 해줍니다. 텍스트를 생성하고 일상적인 함수를 수행할 수도 있어요.
But if you want to get deeper into the code, if you want to be looking in more detail at things like
코드를 좀 더 깊이 파고들고 싶다면 예를 들어, 어떻게 텍스트를 토큰화하고
how how you are tokenizing your text at which models and which parameters you're using to run a model,
어떤 모델과 어떤 매개 변수를 모델 실행에 사용할지 알고 싶다면요 혹은 훈련을
or if you're actually going to go as far as training and be fine tuning your own model to carry out
통해 자신의 모델을 잘 조정해서 추가적인 지식이나 뉘앙스를 가지고
specialist tasks with extra knowledge or nuance.
특수한 작업을 수행할 수 있다면요
At that point, you need to look at the deeper APIs, the lower level APIs, working with Tokenizers
그땐 더 깊은 API를 살펴봐야 합니다 하위 레벨 API요 토큰라이저와 포옹하는 얼굴
and models in Hugging Face.
모델과 작업하는 거죠
Today we're going to be looking at pipelines.
오늘은 파이프라인을 살펴볼 거예요
And then after that we're going to turn to the Tokenizers and models.
그런 다음 토큰라이저와 모델로 넘어가죠
So what can you do with these pipelines?
파이프라인을 어떻게 할 수 있을까요?
So essentially it allows you to take instant advantage of models on the Hugging face hub with two lines
즉, 두 줄의 코드로 얼굴 허브에서 모델을 즉각적으로 이용할 수 있게 해주는 것이죠
It's as simple as that.
아주 간단해요
And I'm going to give you lots of examples and lots of things you can take away so that you can use
많은 예제를 제공할 거예요 여러분이 가져갈 수 있는 많은
it yourself to carry out every day inference tasks.
것도요 매일 추론 작업을 수행하는 데 직접 사용할 수 있도록요
So one classic example, which is one of the easiest ones to start with, is what they call sentiment
가장 쉬운 것 중 하나인 전형적인 예가 바로 정서 분석이에요
Given a sentence saying what is the emotion conveyed by this sentence?
이 문장이 전달하는 감정은 무엇인지 묻는 문장이죠
Uh, then classification, of course, is one of those very traditional machine learning tasks of putting
분류는 물론 아주 전통적인 머신 러닝 과제입니다 물건을 양동이에
things into buckets.
담는 거죠
Named entity recognition is when you can take a sentence and tag the words in that sentence as things
개체 인식이라는 것은 문장을 보고 그 문장의 단어를 사람이냐 장소냐
like whether they are people or whether they are locations or things and so on.
같은 것으로 태그할 수 있는 거예요
Question answering is when you have some context and you want to be able to ask questions about the
질문 답변은 어떤 컨텍스트가 있는데 여러분이 제공하는 컨텍스트에 관해 질문할
context that you provide.
수 있어야 할 때죠
Summarization, of course, is when you have a block of text and you want to turn it into a summary
요약은 텍스트 블록이 있을 때 요약 번역으로 바꾸는
translation.
거예요
Another classic AI task translating between one language and another.
한 언어를 다른 언어로 번역하는 인공지능의 전형적인 작업이죠
So what if I told you that all of these things can be done with two lines of code each?
이 모든 게 각각 코드 2줄로 가능하다면 어떨까요?
Hopefully you would be amazed and you will see it in a moment.
잠시 후에 깜짝 놀라실 거예요
There are some other things you can do as well that become perhaps slightly more advanced.
좀 더 발전된 다른 기능도 할 수 있어요
Text generation actually isn't advanced at all.
문자 생성은 사실 전혀 발전하지 않았어요
It's still just two lines of code.
여전히 코드 2줄일 뿐이죠
It's still super simple, and it's another thing that you will marvel at.
여전히 아주 간단해요 놀랄 만한 또 다른 거죠
But generating images is also very simple, as is audio.
이미지 생성 역시 간단합니다 오디오도 마찬가지죠
It becomes a little bit more than two lines, but it's still very simple and I can't wait to show you.
비트 코드는 두 줄 이상이지만 아주 간단해요 빨리 보여드리고 싶네요
I think that's enough preamble.
서론은 그만하면 됐어요
Let's get straight to it.
Get it, get it 바로 본론으로 들어가죠
Let's go to Google Colab.
구글 콜랍으로 가보죠